pitchrate.com 2013-10-27

# Free Publicity:Privacy Policy

PitchRate.com is committed to protecting your privacy and ensuring you have a positive experience on our website. This policy outlines our personal information handling practices. If you give us personal information, we will treat it according to this policy.

**Collection of your personal information**

When PitchRate.com collects any personal information on our website, we will express our need for the personal data at the point of collection. Personal information is any information that can be used to identify an individual, and may include, but is not limited to, name, email address, postal or other physical address, title, occupation, and other information required to provide this service to the media and experts alike.

**Uses of your personal information**

We will only use your personal information in the way we specify per this policy and the Terms and Conditions of PitchRate.com.  Some of the ways we may use your personal information include:

  * To provide the ability to create personal profile areas.
  * To provide customer feedback and support.
  * To provide marketing or promotional activities on PitchRate.com. 
  * To conduct questionnaires and surveys in order to provide better website services to our customers and end users. Your completion of any questionnaires is voluntary.
  * To allow you to forward information to another individual such Expert to Journalist (although journalist personal email is cloaked, the system requires it to make the data transfer). 
  * To meet obligations set forth in the Terms & Conditions or Privacy Policy.

**Accessing and updating your personal information**

PitchRate.com does not update personal contact information for customers. Please go to the site and change your personal information on the Manage Account page.

.

**Unsubscribing**

You may also unsubscribe from PitchRate.com's overall service via the link provided within the site.

**Managing Email**

You may manage the notifications sent to you via your personal email on the PitchRate.com site.  

**Sale of Information**

We do not sell or rent your personal information to third-parties for marketing purposes unless you have granted us permission to do so.

**Sharing your personal information**

In some instances, PitchRate.com may collect non-personal (aggregate or demographic) data through cookies, web logs, and web beacons. This information is used to better understand and improve the usability, performance, and effectiveness of the PitchRate.com.com website.

We may share your personal information for purposes of data processing or storage.

We may also share your personal information with authorized third-party agents or contractors in order to provide a requested service or transaction. For example, if we need to ship something to you, we must share your name and address with a shipping company. We only provide third-party agents with the minimum amount of personal information necessary to complete the requested service or transaction.

We may respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process by disclosing your personal information and other related information, if necessary. We also may choose to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

We may collect and possibly share personal information and any other additional information available to us in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of PitchRate.com's terms of use, or as otherwise required by law.

While navigating PitchRate.com's web site you may be directed to content or functionality that is hosted by a third party supplier, not hosted on PitchRate.com.  When information is collected on behalf of PitchRate.com exclusively, PitchRate.com's privacy policy will be referenced on the site and will govern how your information is used. For other, non-PitchRate.com sites, the site owner's privacy policy will be referenced. It is PitchRate.com's practice to require such suppliers to handle information in a manner consistent with PitchRate.com's privacy and security policies.

We will ask you for your opt-in consent to share your personal information with a third party for any other reason.

**Security of your personal information**

PitchRate.com is committed to protecting the personal information you share with us. We utilize a combination of security technologies, procedures, and organizational measures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure.

While we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure the security of the information you transmit.  We recommend you to take every precaution in protecting your personal information when you are on the Internet. For example, change your passwords often, use a combination of letters and numbers when creating passwords, and make sure you use a secure browser.

**Cookies**

PitchRate.com utilizes cookies, which expire within one month of being set.  PitchRate.com uses them to help member users and we do not share them across sites.

We use multiple third parties to monitor web traffic, statistics, advertisement 'click-through', and other activities on PitchRate.com's sites. Where authorized by PitchRate.com, such third parties may use cookies, PitchRate.com's web log files, web beacons, and other monitoring technologies to compile anonymous aggregate statistics on PitchRate.com's website visitors.

We also include web beacons in HTML-formatted e-mail newsletters in order to count how many newsletters (or particular articles, links, etc.) are being accessed.

Current versions of web browsers offer enhanced user controls regarding the placement and duration of both first and third party cookies. Search for "cookies" under your web browser's Help menu for more information on cookie management features available to you.

**Data retention**

PitchRate.com will not retain your personal information longer than is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected or as required by applicable laws or regulations.

**Linked websites**

Our websites may provide links to other third-party websites which are outside our control and not covered by this policy. We encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on these (and all) sites.

**Newsgroups/forums**

PitchRate.com newsgroups and forums are public. Please consider this before posting material to them.

**Children's privacy**

PitchRate.com does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have collected personal information on a child under the age of 13, we will delete that data from our systems. PitchRate.com encourages parents and guardians to go online with their children. Here are a few tips to help make a child's online experience safer:

Teach children never to give personal information (such as name, address, phone number, school, etc.) unless supervised by a parent or responsible adult.

Know the sites your children are visiting and which sites are appropriate.

Look for website privacy policies. Know how your child's information is treated.

Please visit the [FTC's website](http://business.ftc.gov/privacy-and-security/children%E2%80%99s-privacy) for more tips on protecting children's privacy online.

**Need assistance?**

Need help with an update, access, or unsubscribe request? Please contact us via [info@pitchrate.com](mailto:info@pitchrate.com).  To aid in processing your request, please include the following details: your full name and email address and whether you registered as an expert or journalist.
